Subtitles by explosiveskull
( SHOUTS OF ENCOURAGEMENT AND BACKGROUND CHATTER )
( FOOTBALL COMMENTATOR SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
( SHOUTS OF ENCOURAGEMENT )
MALE COMMENTATOR : Amira 's brought down just outside the area .
The keeper catches it comfortably .
It now looks like there will be a substitution for the blues .
Gentry replaces Penny .
- Take your time . - BARMAN : You what ?
Big head on that , mate . Thank you .
No problem .
MAN : Oh , yeah , two weeks straight drinking , man . What a great time .
Had a great time . Felt better when I got home .
- ( LAUGHS ) - Easy .
- What about ... What about Ibiza ? - No , we 're too old for Ibiza .
What are you talking about ? You 're never too old for the island , mate .
That 's what people who are too old for Ibiza say . Where are the crisps ?
Oh , I said , " Can I have crisps for that guy , "
I pointed to you , and he said you 're not allowed to have crisps any more .
Said you 're only allowed salads .
Fucking dickhead .
It 's just what he said , Dom , I 'm sorry .
That 's harsh , man .
Why don 't we go to ... Boom , Amsterdam ?
- No , it 's too touristy now , innit ? - All right , TripAdvisor .
- I 'm not getting off my head again . - Tuscany ?
- Yeah , yeah , no , good wines . - No .
- DOM : Berlin , then ? - Nein .
- Belgium ? - Belgium ?
Mate , no-one 's ever been to Belgium by choice .
- What 's in Belgium ? - Beers that are like 42 % or something .
What about hiking ? Hiking in Sweden ?
- Hiking ? - Yeah .
- Hiking . - That 's a good shout .
Come on , man , let 's do something good .
- What 's it called again ? - The King 's Trail .
It kind of runs up between Sweden and Norway .
You can go there in the summer .
Oh , yeah , yeah , it 's like the Appalachian Trail , right ?
Yeah . Apart from there 's more history than hill billies .
We wanna do something different . I just don 't want go to Amsterdam .
You wanna mix it up .
Yeah , it 's not like we 're 21 any more .
Oh , look , there 's that ... I 'm gonna get a bottle .
- Who 's on it ? - No way . School night , mate .
I wanna crack on .
So no-one ... Anyone wanna come with me ?
- Nope . - Come on , Robert .
- Yeah , go on , then . - Oh , man .
- Bad idea . - Anyone want any sweets or anything ?
You 're not involved in that , are you ?
- I 'm getting an Uber . - Yeah , good .
Don 't you think that it 's getting harder now to have a good time ?
Do you know that Phil actually suggested making this brunch ?
Fucking brunch . I 'm not , I 'm not ,
I 'm not gonna plan a lads ' holiday over a fucking avocado on toast , mate .
- I 'm just ... I 'm not doing it . - Avocado 's all right .
Do you really wanna go hiking ? Hiking , for fun ?
- Yeah . - In fucking Sweden ?
Yeah , I do . I dunno ,
I just wanna test myself a little , you know . A challenge .
What would be a challenge is getting Dom on the side of a mountain .
Where 's the vodka ?
Just a shame , you know . It 's a shame . It 's a shame what he 's become .
Yeah . Yeah , big shame , yeah .
Big successful businessman with a beautiful wife and children .
Yeah , no , it 's a ...
( WHIMPERING )
- ( EXHALES SHARPLY ) - Don 't fucking argue , you cunt !
There 's more ! Where the fuck is it , huh ?
- ( WOMAN SOBBING ) - Stop fucking crying !
( BOTTLES RATTLE )
Don 't fucking move .
- Give me your wallet . - MAN 1 : Right , give it to him .
ROBERT : Okay , okay , it 's okay .
MAN 1 : Don 't just stand there , do it !
MAN 2 : Give me your fucking wallet .
- What else you got ? - MAN 1 : What else you got ?
- ( BOTTLE SMASHES ) - MAN 1 : Just take his watch .
- Give me the fucking watch . - All right , no problem , here .
- MAN 1 : Do it ! - ROBERT : Okay , all right .
MAN 2 : And the ring .
ROBERT : No . It 's my wedding ring .
- MAN 1 : We don 't give a fuck ! - MAN 2 : Just give me the fucking ring .
- MAN 1 : Just take it off him ! - ROBERT : No . Look , you 've done enough .
It ... Just leave .
Take it the fuck off him !
ROBERT : Come on .
MAN 1 : Listen , you take that ring off or I will fuck you up !
- Look , I 'm not ... - ( ROARS )
- ( WOMAN SCREAMS ) - ( GASPS )
MAN 2 : Oh , fuck ! Mate , what are you doing ?
MAN 1 : I told you .
- MAN 2 : Fucking hell , mate ! - ( GASPS )
What are you doing ?
MAN 1 : It 's all right .
- For fuck 's sake . Leave it . - MAN 2 : Right , let 's go , let 's go !
( RUNNING FOOTSTEPS )
( WIND HOWLS )
( WIND BLOWS )
( TENT UNZIPS )
Morning .
Fuck me , it 's cold .
I 'll get the coffees on .
- Morning , bud . - Morning .
- How did you sleep ? - ( GROANS )
Like I 'd just walked up a big fucking mountain , man .
One night down , two to go , mate .
Makes you feel insignificant , right ?
- DOM : Speak for yourself . - Come on , man , where 's your soul ?
These mountains were smashed out by Nordic gods with big bastard hammers .
You know what they have on walking trails in England ?
- Pubs . - Yeah , whatever .
Don 't tell me you 're not impressed .
Yeah , yeah , these are new boots . Reduced to 200 quid .
- Memory foam as well . - But you still need to break them in .
Yeah , definitely .
It 's just basic common sense , Phil .
Okay , I think I 've found a spot .
Just up the top of that hill .
- Fuck me . - It 's beautiful .
( BREATHES HEAVILY AND SNIFFS )
Jesus ... Christ !
Oh , fuck every hill in the world .
Shall we do this ?
- Bo will be up there waiting for him . - Man , I hated that dog .
He was a good man .
The best of us .
It should never have happened .
It should never have happened but it did ...
- And all we can do is remember him . - ( SNIFFS )
( SNIFFS )
Robert , we miss you , mate .
DOM : We haven 't seen her .
I can 't remember the last time I saw her .
PHIL : Yeah , I mean , she mentioned Gayle .
DOM : Yeah , well , they get on .
( INDISTINCT CONVERSATION )
Rob would have loved this place .
Except we wouldn 't be here , though , would we ?
We 'd be on some terrible lads ' holiday that he would have hated .
I 've said it before , I don 't care what anyone says ,
it wasn 't your fault , mate .
- Fucking hell , is that the lodge ? - I think it is , yeah .
Ah . I thought we were further out than that .
Uh-uh .
When we get back I was thinking I might stop on a few days .
Maybe get out there , do a little bit more hiking .
- What do you think , man ? - I dunno , mate .
Come all this way , we gotta make the most of it .
No , I think this is enough for me .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
What are you doing , man ? Here , give it here .
You 've done it the wrong way round . Give it here . Unclip the pole .
DOM : Christ !
( WIND HOWLS )
PHIL : Oh , this is awful in almost every conceivable way .
DOM : There are some , Phil , who consider this character building .
Quite frankly , right now , Sweden can lick my bridge .
- Lick your what ? - My bridge .
- Jesus Christ , the bridge . - Oh , you mean the perineum .
- Yeah , the gooch . The bridge . - Yeah , yeah , yeah .
- Argh ! - ( THUD )
Fuck !
- Come on , let 's get you up . - Argh !
Fuck , shit !
All right , come on . Easy , easy .
- Come on , mate , you 're all right . - Up , up , up .
Yeah , all right , easy .
- Oh , fuck . - Walk about a bit on it .
- Argh ! - Give it a walk around .
That 's it .
You 're okay .
Argh ! No , it 's twisted . It 's twisted .
- Can you put your full weight on it ? - Hurts like a son of a bitch .
You could probably walk it off , couldn 't you ?
No , no , it 's my meniscus . I 've done it before , it 's fucked .
We 'll get him something to lean on . Phil , can you get the rods , please ?
What we thinking , Dom ?
' Cause the trail goes right round those mountains there ,
and it 's probably , what , six hours till we camp ?
Another eight round to the lodge .
What we thinking ?
Fuck me .
I 'm not doing 14 hours on this . Okay , man ?
Let 's get the map .
- Wanna try your phone as well ? - No , no need .
- Well , there 's no reception anyway . - Cheers , man .
Luke , my office .
What do you think ?
I think we could be carrying him out
of here like a fucking Egyptian princess
- if we 're not careful . - Probably not as bad as he says it is .
Almost certainly not as bad as he says it is ,
but it 's not gonna stop him moaning the whole way back , is it ?
There is another way out of this , man .
What ?
Well , you saw it last night . The lodge .
It 's not that far as the crow flies . Look , if we go south-west ,
through here , we cut the journey in half .
- What , through the forest ? - Yeah , why not ?
Little off-trail hiking .
Could be exciting . Might even do us some good .
We could be kicking back by the evening time .
I think we need this .
Look , why don 't me and you leave them here with the food
and then we can go back , get some help ?
No fucking way you 're leaving us on this fucking mountain .
I can walk . All right ?
If you know a quicker route , let 's do it .
( PANTING )
- How 's the knee , Dom-Dom ? - Killing me . How 's your mum ?
Unnecessary , innit ?
- Are there bears in this forest ? - Course there 's fucking bears .
Big bastards as well .
DOM : Should have gone to Vegas .
PHIL : You 'd have found something to fall over in Vegas , too .
DOM : Yeah , a massive pile of tits .
Shithouse .
Everything in this bastard country is a relic .
Strange place to park , innit ?
My next door neighbour 's got one of those .
My eldest is absolutely obsessed by it .
I got a hand job in one of those once , at a festival .
Thanks , Phil . What a beautiful story .
- We sure this is a good idea ? - What 's up ? You scared of the woods ?
DOM : Now , is it me or is it really quiet in here ?
All right , don 't shit your pants . The trees soak up the sound .
That 's what trees do .
DOM : Hiking was easier yesterday .
LUKE : We weren 't in the forest yesterday .
DOM : No , we bloody weren 't .
The sooner we get going , the sooner we get to the town ,
the sooner we get to the bar , the sooner we get drunk .
The Swedes were big into logging , until the 1950s .
- Then they decided to pack it in . - That 's interesting .
Which is why Sweden is an untouched land of natural beauty
and Britain is a car park .
DOM : If you love Sweden so much , why don 't you marry it ?
Right , time out .
Dom , what did Gayle say
when you told her you were going on a hiking holiday ?
She said , " Who are you ? What have you done with my husband ? "
Oh , here we go , photo op .
- Here we go . - ( CHUCKLES ) Scott of the Antarctic .
- Fucking Amelia Earhart over there . - Wallop .
Yes , that 's it . Let 's get a selfie while we 're here .
- DOM : Selfie ? Really ? - You too , Luke , come on .
- Let 's preserve this magic moment . - It 's a beautiful thing .
Here we go .
Everyone get in . One , two , three , and Brexit .
- ( LENS CLICKS ) - Boom .
- Yes . - Yeah , yeah , four twats in a forest .
Yeah .
( TWIGS SNAP )
My stomach is beginning to eat itself .
Yeah , I could do a steak .
Big fat , juicy steak .
One peppercorn sauce , one hand-cooked chips .
Side salad . Nice tumbler of Scotch .
And a big fat cigar at the end .
PHIL : Ah , man , I could go for some sushi right now .
Yeah , some red wine instead of white .
Lashings of wasabi .
Big Mac , plastic tray , by myself , no-one to talk to .
- Can I have a kebab , please , mate ? - Donner ?
No , chicken shish , please .
Rob liked a donner . You remember that ?
Yeah .
Every Saturday night at uni .
There he was , pissed , covered in grease .
What the fuck ?
What the fuck is it ?
( FLIES BUZZING )
- DOM : Why is it ripped open ? - It 's been gutted .
Yeah , but why hang it like that ?
I mean , would someone do that ?
Well , it didn 't fucking put itself there , that 's for sure .
- Could be hunters out here . - What , bait ?
Possibly .
Or it 's the bit they don 't show you in the nature documentaries .
What could do that , though ?
- A bear . - Do bears do that ?
I don 't know , Dominic , I 'm not a fucking bear expert .
- It 's still bleeding . - So ?
So it means that whatever did that , we should go . It 's a fresh kill .
Yeah , we should go .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
( THUNDER CRASHING )
DOM : Fucking Jesus Christ !
- Fuck . - ( THUNDER CRASHING )
- Where the hell are we , Hutch ? - Let me check .
PHIL : This is ridiculous , man .
- HUTCH : We should pitch the tents . - What ?
We should pitch the tents !
So we 're giving up making it back to town tonight , then ?
I don 't see we have much choice , Philip .
Guys .
- What is it ? What is it ? - Look at this .
- Huh ? - Look .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
- HUTCH : Well , how about that ? - PHIL : What is that ?
Is that a house ?
- Come on . - Thank Christ .
- DOM : Hey , Hutch . Wait a minute ! - Come on !
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
- DOM : Can you see anything ? - It looks empty !
DOM : We should leave it alone , then .
- Let 's kick it in . - No fucking way .
We need to get undercover , mate .
- Phil , give us a hand . - All right , come on , then .
Wait , wait , wait , wait ! We can 't just break in .
We can 't stay out here all night .
On three , yeah ?
- One , two , three . - ( THUD )
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
( SHORT ROAR )
( SHORT SHRIEK )
- Luke , you 're getting soaked . - Did you hear that ?
No , I didn 't hear anything . Come on .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
This is clearly the house we 'll get murdered in .
HUTCH : It 's not as bad as our uni accommodation .
That 's the shape on the tree , I think .
Guys , this place is definitely abandoned , yeah ?
Abandoned ? Who 'd have moved in ?
HUTCH : Whoever it was , they were packing . Look at that .
- I don 't like this place . - Not too keen on it myself , mate ,
but it 's a lesser-of-two-evils kind of situation .
Hutch . I definitely just heard something outside .
Well , maybe you did , Lukey .
We 're not the only animals in the woods .
Right , let 's see if we can get this stove working .
We 'll need stuff to burn .
- PHIL : Like what ? - HUTCH : Anything made of wood 'll do .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
PHIL : We 're gonna smash the place up , are we ?
- And what if the homeowners come back ? - Fuck ' em .
Anyone who lives here has more to worry
about than their table being on fire .
Might be some stuff to burn up there .
Go on , Phil , you 're nearest .
- What ? - Go on .
- Do you want me to come with you ? - No .
( ALL CHUCKLING )
- ( CHAIR SMASHES ) - HUTCH : Wa-hey , that 's it , lad !
( LAUGHTER )
Dickheads .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
( DOOR CREAKS )
Guys , get the fuck up here right now !
What now ?
Oh , shit .
Oh , my God .
What the fuck is that ?
- That 's witchcraft . - Huh ?
That 's what that is , that 's witchcraft .
LUKE : Is that meant to be a person ?
PHIL : What , with no head and antlers for hands ?
If I hear anything coming down the stairs ...
Don 't . Fucking hell !
I 'm going downstairs to get that fire started .
You guys can stay up here if you want .
- Yep . Good idea . - Come on .
LUKE : Looked like that fucking thing in the tree .
HUTCH : Could be idolising a spirit or a deity .
Some kind of pagan or Nordic shit .
Like an offering or something .
Yeah , well , I almost offered up a massive shit when I saw it .
- I thought they worshipped Odin . - Well , that is Nordic .
Who knows what they 're into out here ? Living here , in the middle of nowhere .
Sun goes down , don 't come up for six months .
You 're bound to go fucking mental in the winter .
We should probably burn this place down when we leave .
- Fucking well up for burning it down . - ( CHUCKLES )
Listen , though , I think that , um ,
when we wake up tomorrow ,
we should think about just going back out the way we came .
We don 't need to wilfully add another day to the trip , do we ?
- Let 's just stick to the shortcut ... - My old scoutmaster used to say
" If the shortcut was a shortcut , it would be called a route . "
Why pretend you were in the Scouts ? You were never in the Scouts .
Where did I get the quote from , then ?
Guys , right , we have a map , we have a compass ,
we have supplies .
So as long as we don 't panic , as long as we don 't fuck ourselves
- we 're gonna be absolutely okay . - DOM : No-one 's fucking anyone .
- Who knows ? It could be a long night . - No-one 's fucking anybody .
( CHUCKLES )
DOM : We 're in sleeping bags , for crying out loud .
It could get messy .
I 'll give any of you a grand to go upstairs and sleep with that thing .
Absolutely no way .
- My wife would never forgive me . - No , she wouldn 't .
- Good night . - Yeah , all right , okay .
Couple of hours , soon as it 's light , we 'll get out .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
( FAINT KNOCKING )
( FAINT GROWL )
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
( THUNDER CRASHING )
( STORM STOPS )
( WHISPERS ) Hutch .
( GASPS )
( BOTTLES RATTLE )
( INHALES AND EXHALES DEEPLY )
( PANTING )
( EXHALES SHARPLY )
( SCREAMS )
- ( HUTCH SCREAMS AND GASPS ) - Hutch ?
Hutch ?
Mate , wake up .
Mate . It 's okay , it 's okay , it 's okay .
- Where the fuck am I ? - We 're in that house .
We 're in that fucking house , okay ?
Get up , okay ? Get up .
Where 's the ... Where 's my fucking ...
Jesus Christ .
I 've pissed myself .
( SOBS ) Gayle .
LUKE : Dom ?
DOM : ( WHIMPERS ) Gayle !
- LUKE : Dom . - ( WHIMPERS )
Dom !
- Gayle ! - Wake up . Mate , mate , it 's okay .
( CRYING )
Get up , mate .
Wake up .
Where 's Phil ?
- Where the fuck 's ... - ( CREAKS FROM UPSTAIRS )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( UNDER HIS BREATH ) Oh , fuck .
Phil .
Fuck !
- Phil . Phil , what are you doing ? - ( GROANS )
- Phil , what are you doing ? - ( PHIL GROANS )
- It 's okay . - ( HYPERVENTILATES )
It 's okay . Mate , get up , okay ?
What 's this ? What 's this ?
I don 't know . I don 't know , mate .
Get up , okay ?
DOM : Just grab everything . Just shove it in the bags , let 's go .
Can we fucking hurry up , yeah ?
I want to get out of here now !
DOM : Oh , for fuck 's sake .
- We shouldn 't be here . - LUKE : It 's a warning .
No , we don 't know that . We do not know that .
- It 's a warning . - Fuck !
Listen .
Hutch , we just go out the way we came in , okay ?
- We go north-east . - HUTCH : It 's a knee-jerk plan .
- Guys . - It 's a bad plan .
- Mate . - Hey !
Hey !
Is that a path ?
No , Dom , south-west is this way , mate .
South-west can go and fuck itself .
You said we were getting out of this forest yesterday .
The storm slowed us down . What do you want ?
So did the dead thing hanging in the trees
and the spooky fucking house !
Um , can we go ?
We don 't even know where that goes .
We could end up in Norway for all we know .
Great ! You know , I 'm sick of this off-road bollocks . Okay ?
A path means civilisation .
Dom .
Marvellous .
So are we gonna talk about it , then , or not ?
Because I 'd really like to talk about it .
- I 'd rather not , mate . - You 'd rather not ?
I woke up stark bollock naked in front of that thing ,
praying to it , and I 'd love someone to explain it to me .
It was a nightmare , Phil . What 's commonly known as a nightmare .
- What happened to you , then , mate ? - We all did . We all had nightmares .
We got spooked and we had bad dreams .
- All right ? - Yeah . Leave it out , mate .
Hang on , mate . You were screaming and shouting at the top of your voice .
You were shouting " Gayle ! "
- Have you ever done that before ? - I said leave it out , Luke .
- Something made me do that . - Press on .
Bad dreams or not , I 'd never have done that . Something was in that house .
For fuck 's sake , Phil ! Listen to yourself , mate .
I 'm a bit fucking humiliated
about being found in my kegs covered in piss .
All right ? I don 't really wanna psychoanalyse it .
I don 't wanna play fucking make-believe because , right now ,
we have some real fucking problems .
Like finding out which way this fucking path ends up .
Enough of the bullshit ghost stories , okay ?
You 're starting to sound like my daughters .
Outside I 'd never have done that , mate .
PHIL : Something 's not right here .
( ECHOING BREATH )
- Did you say south-west , yeah ? - Yes .
- Which way is south-west ? - That ridge up there .
- What , towards the light ? - Yeah . We 're just tracking along it .
Five more minutes on this path and I 'm pulling rank .
You see these things ? Man-made .
We 're getting somewhere .
( HUTCH BREATHES HEAVILY )
- HUTCH : Should we have a look ? - Absolutely not .
- Let 's keep going . - Yep .
We can still get out of here today .
LUKE : Dom ...
Dom , maybe we should think about this .
Dom .
Guys , I just need a minute .
My knee 's killing me .
These are the wrong fucking shoes .
Er , Dom , you might have to push through the pain barrier a bit , mate .
- We can 't keep going at this pace . - Screw you .
I 'm through the pain barrier . I 'm in bloody agony .
No . I think you 're uncomfortable . There 's a difference .
Oh , I 'm sorry , I didn 't realise you were a doctor .
Go give yourself a fucking prostate exam and leave me in peace , yeah ?
Dom , come on , get up .
No .
Dom , I want out of these woods now .
Please get up .
This is fucking ridiculous .
I 'm gonna go to the top of that ridge , see if I can see anything .
Yeah . Yeah , good idea , man .
- To the ridge , straight back . - Got it .
- Don 't go too far . - Yeah , got it !
( PANTING )
Fuck !
( BREATHES HEAVILY )
( INHALES AND EXHALES DEEPLY )
- ( INHALES ) - ( TWIG SNAPS )
( ROARING )
( BRANCHES CRACKING )
LUKE : Guys !
- Everything okay ? - There 's something up there .
DOM : What are you talking about ?
- There 's something in those woods . - What do you mean ?
- Something fucking big . - HUTCH : Like an animal ? What ?
Can we not do this , please ?
Can we all agree to not start losing our fucking shit in here ?
- There is fucking something up there . - Shut up .
Okay , listen , I 'm not trying to fucking freak you out
but I woke up last night and there was some fucking ...
And look at this .
- What ... - What the fuck is that ?
Nothing has done that to you . You ...
You 're on your own . You 've done it to yourself .
- I fucking what ? - You walked into a fucking tree .
Why do you have to fucking deny everything I say ?
Because I do not value your judgement , Luke .
And I wanna get the fuck out of here .
Listen , mate , we wouldn 't be here if it wasn 't for you !
No , we wouldn 't be here if it wasn 't for you !
Dom , shut up .
Come on , what do you mean by that ?
Track it back .
- You know what I 'm talking about . - No . No , I don 't .
I don 't , no . Why don 't you just , er ...
- Fucking come out and say it ? - Come on , guys . This is bullshit !
- Come on , mate . - Now there it is !
Now he 's got some fucking fight in him , yeah ?
Well , where was that with Rob ?
You fight your friends , you can 't stand up for them .
You are not my fucking friend any more .
No , I am not .
- No , you 're fucking not . - HUTCH : Oh , for fuck 's sake , guys .
No , you are fucking not . Okay ?
Do you know what ? I am fucking done with you .
Not a drop of blood on you .
Fucking coward .
- What ? - Dom , will you shut the fuck up .
No , hang on , Hutch , mate . Hang on . Hang on . What ?
Fucking what ?
He has his skull cracked in half
and you come out of there
without a drop of blood on you . Argh !
- HUTCH : What the fuck are you doing ? - PHIL : Dom , are you all right , mate ?
- He 's broken my nose ! - Shut up .
You 've not broken your nose , all right ? Don 't start your shit now .
You keep quiet if you want , but somebody 's got to say something .
This is exactly the kind of situation
where people fall out and we need to be ...
Where you going ? We need to be working together , man !
Luke . Fucking hell . Luke .
Luke .
Is that what you think ? Eh ? That it was my fault ?
That I should have stood up ?
I don 't know .
Looks like someone was here .
Are we stopping ?
What the fuck is that ?
Yeah , what is that , man ? Some sort of fabric , I think .
( STRAINS )
( GRUNTS ) I think it 's a tent or something .
It 's a credit card .
Anna Eriksen . Expires 1984 .
That 's a bad sign , isn 't it ?
Just leaving your tent behind and your shoes ?
Guys . Guys , seriously , come on .
We 're not gonna be these people , right ? Okay ?
Because we registered at the lodge .
And in five hours ' time , five hours ' time ,
they are gonna report us missing .
We 're on a path in the woods . It 's near a hiking trail .
This is where people get found , right ?
It 's getting dark again .
( GROANS )
( EXHALES )
Oh , thanks .
Thank you . Thank you .
How are you doing ?
I 'm looking forward to the rescue party .
( CHUCKLES )
Dom 's knee is getting worse , not better .
Phil 's not looking great .
You 're the strongest . You should try and get out , get help .
I 'll stay with these two .
- You think so ? - Definitely .
I 'll get you fixed up in the morning .
- Take the compass , head south-west . - Okay .
- Keep south-west . - Okay .
- Good man , mate . - Yeah .
How are we doing here , mate ?
Let 's have a look at this .
HUTCH : Ooh , looks nasty , that , man .
( RUSTLING )
PHIL : Yeah , it 's not good .
- HUTCH : Have you put anything on it ? - No , I haven 't got anything .
HUTCH : Maybe Dom 's got something in his backpack .
PHIL : Fucking shoes .
HUTCH : That looks grim .
( CLICK OF TORCH SWITCH )
( LIQUID SLOSHES )
( DISTANT CRACK OF A BRANCH )
( RUSTLING )
( THUMP )
( FOOTFALLS APPROACHING )
( LABOURED BREATHING )
( FOOTFALLS APPROACHING CLOSER )
( ROARING IN NEAR DISTANCE )
( LUKE BREATHES HEAVILY )
( CRACK OF A BRANCH )
( GASPS )
( GARBLED SPEECH )
( CRACKLING AND THUMPING FOOTFALLS )
( BREATHES HEAVILY )
( ANGUISHED CRY )
Phil , Phil !
- Phil , Phil , Phil ! - It was here .
( PHIL GRUNTS )
- ( PHILE HYPERVENTILATES ) - ( PANTING )
- Where 's Hutch ? - I don 't know , man .
- Where 's Hutch ? - All I saw was shadows .
- What ? - I don 't know !
It just ... It took him .
Hutch ?
- ( GROANS ) - Hutch !
- Get up , Hutch has gone . - What ?
Hutch has gone !
( HUTCH SCREAMS )
( ROARING )
( FEROCIOUS ROARING )
- ( DISTANT SCREAMING ) - Oh , fuck .
( SCREAM FADES )
- PHIL : What we gonna do ? - LUKE : I don 't know .
Hutch ?
Hutch !
- LUKE : Hutch ! - Luke ...
DOM : Luke , we 're getting turned around out here .
- Hutch ! - We should try and retrace our steps .
Everything we have is in the tents , Luke .
- He 's fucking screaming . - I know .
But if we run around in circles , we 're gonna get fucking lost . Okay ?
We need to get back to the camp and get our bearings . Yeah ?
Fuck ... Fuck .
We 'll find the tents and come back for him .
( INHALES SHARPLY )
( WHIMPERS )
Is that ...
Is that Hutch ?
( PANTING )
Oh , my God !
( DOM CONTINUES CRYING OUT )
( PANTING )
Oh , fuck .
Come on !
- Did he have the map ? - No .
- What are we gonna tell Catherine ? - I don 't know .
- What about his kids ? - Listen , okay ? Just calm down .
We need to get out of here , now . We need to move .
We can 't leave him here .
We can 't bury him . Okay ?
We 'll send people to come and get him .
Fucking hell , we don 't know where we are .
- It put him there , didn 't it ? - What ?
It knew we were gonna come this way
and we were supposed to find him , weren 't we ?
LUKE : Oh , for fuck 's sakes .
You don 't fucking do this . You keep your , your shit together .
Shush . He 's right .
I 'm not ...
I 'm not leaving him like this .
( PANTING AND MOANING )
- We should say something . - We need to go .
It 's gonna come back .
Dom , come on .
Come on .
PHIL : It was at that house .
We had those nightmares and it followed us , didn 't it ?
Yeah .
It followed us from that house and it did that to Hutch .
Did you actually see it yesterday ?
I don 't know what I saw .
Well ... I did see it ,
while I was up on that ridge , and the trees were the same as this .
Oh , Jesus Christ .
It was big , okay ?
It had to be to put that fucking elk in the tree .
It was hunters , pagan fucking hill billies from those houses .
No-one 's lived in those houses for years .
- Fucking hell ! - Keep your voice down .
- There are houses in this forest . - Keep it down .
There are people and they killed our fucking friend !
Shut the fuck up . Shut up !
Keep your fucking voice down .
There are three of us and there is one of it .
And I 've got a fucking knife .
So we are gonna keep walking in the direction that Hutch said
until we get out of this fucking forest . Do you hear me ?
( PANTING )
- Oh , my God . - ( RETCHES )
- ( GROANS ) - ( MOANING )
You see ? There 's people .
- Are we following these ? - Course not .
DOM : We shouldn 't go that way .
Okay . Okay .
LUKE : South-west is up .
DOM : I 'm tired , man .
Ah !
( PANTING )
( GASPS )
It 's okay .
Come on , mate , get up .
Got inside my head , man .
Made me pray to that thing in the house .
I can 't get it out of my fucking head .
Come on , mate , get up .
We 're far away from that now .
Come on , you can do it .
( WHEEZING )
( PANTING )
( GROANS )
Dom , look . Look .
Phil .
( PANTING )
Where are you going ?
( WIND HOWLS )
( PANTING )
We 're close .
Guys ! I can see the end !
I can see the end .
I shall ... I shall try ...
Guys ?
Guys , you gotta see this .
Dom ?
Phil .
- What you doing ? - PHIL : We heard something .
DOM : Phil .
( PHIL SCREAMS )
( SCREAMING )
( GROWLING )
( GROANS )
You can 't run .
Dom ...
Dom !
Phil ?
- ( RUSTLING ) - ( GASPS )
( GROWLING )
( BRANCHES CRACKING )
( GROWLS )
( RUSTLING AND FOOTFALLS )
( DOM SHUSHING )
What the ...
( PANTING ) You 're alive , you 're alive . Where 's Phil ?
I just heard something coming and it , it just took him .
What did you see ? What did it look like ?
I don 't know . It 's fast .
It 's fucking hunting us .
Jesus Christ . I thought I 'd die .
I don 't wanna die , I don 't wanna die alone .
Look at me . Look at me . Look at me .
I am not going to leave you . Okay ?
- ( WHIMPERS ) - Okay ?
- Do you think it 's gonna come back ? - Yes .
Yeah .
But I think I might have found a way out .
Do you think you can move your leg ?
Yeah , a little .
Okay , okay .
Piggy back ?
- I 'm afraid we 're gonna have to run . - Yeah .
- I know . - Are you ready ?
In a minute . In a minute .
( THUD )
Let 's go on " three . "
Okay ?
One ...
Two ...
Three .
Come on .
( CRASHING )
( GROWLING )
( RUSTLING )
( CREAKING )
- ( CRASHING ) - ( CRIES OUT )
( ROARING )
( GROWLING )
DOM : His eyes !
Argh !
( PANTING )
LUKE : There 's a path .
( DOM GASPING )
Oh , fuck .
Oh , my God . No , no , no , no , no !
- Phil ! - No , we gotta go !
Phil !
( DOM CRYING OUT )
( CRACKING AND ROARING )
Hello ?
Please !
( ROARING )
Come on . Get up , get up , get up .
( STRAINING AND GROANING )
( DOOR SLAMS SHUT )
( MUSIC PLAYS ON GRAMAPHONE )
( THUD )
- DOM : ( WHISPERS ) Luke . - Mmm ?
Wake up .
- ( UNNATURAL WHISPERING ) - What the fuck ?
- ( UNNATURAL WHISPERING ) - ( PANTING )
- What is that ? - I don 't know . I don 't fucking know .
( CHATTERING )
Okay , okay .
What can you see ?
I see people .
- Two , three ... Four . - What are they doing ?
It looks like they 're building .
Putting something together . Building something .
DOM : What the hell do they want ?
Those fuckers .
I 've gotta get out of here .
Can you reach the table ?
- Why ? - Break the glass .
Cut the ropes .
Go on . Go on , Luke .
Yes .
Go on , Luke .
( RATTLING )
( SOFTLY ) Fuck .
( CRUNCHING )
Is that water ? Water ?
What are you doing ?
( MAN SPEAKS SWEDISH )
What ?
Come on .
No , give him some . No , give him some .
( SPEAKS SWEDISH )
- No ! - What are you doing ?
Oh ! Luke ! Help !
LUKE : Dom !
- ( GRUNTS ) - Dom !
( GROANS )
LUKE : Dom !
Dom !
( FOOTFALLS ABOVE )
- ( THUD ) - DOM : Argh !
- Oh , please don 't ! - Dom !
- ( UNNATURAL WHISPERING ) - Oh , God , no !
- ( DOM WAILING ) - ( UNNATURAL WHISPERING )
( DOM SCREAMING )
( SPEAKS SWEDISH ) They prepare for sacrifice . Over soon .
( ANGUISHED CRIES )
( UNNATURAL WHISPERING )
( WHIMPERS )
( MEN SPEAK IN SWEDISH )
( DOOR IS SHUT AND BOLTED )
You okay ?
( GROANS )
LUKE : Dom ?
Are you okay , mate ?
I never told you about my nightmare .
I saw these people , offering me to that thing .
Dead hands .
Gripping me .
And I saw ... Gayle .
I saw my wife .
I 'm gonna die here , Luke .
No . No . No , you 're not . I couldn 't lose all of you .
They 're gonna kill me . Do you understand ?
They are not .
They 're not gonna kill you because I 'm not gonna let them kill you , okay ?
Listen to me .
You 're gonna get out of here
and you 're gonna burn this fucking place to the ground behind you .
Do you understand ?
You don 't stop . You keep going .
You live .
And you tell my wife ...
I tried to get back to her .
I 'm not gonna do that , cos I don 't need to do that . Okay ?
Luke .
I don 't need to do that . I don 't need to do that .
Okay ? Okay ?
( GASPS )
( CROWD MURMUR IN SWEDISH )
( PANTING )
( CROWD CHANTING )
Come on . Come on .
DOM : What the hell is this ?
You fucking stupid pricks .
Why don 't we do this , yeah ?
( SHOUTS ) What are you waiting for ?
( SOFTLY ) Come on .
Come on .
What are you waiting for !
( BRANCHES CRACKING )
( ROARING )
Come on .
Fucking come on .
- ( SNAPPING ) - ( GROANS )
( GROANS )
( RUSTLING )
( HEAVY FOOTFALLS APPROACHING )
( HEAVY FOOTFALLS AND GROWLING )
Gayle ?
Gayle !
Dom ?
( PANTING AND GROANING )
DOM : Gayle !
Gayle ?
- GAYLE : Dom . - Gayle ?
( SCREAMS )
( GASPS )
( MUTTERING )
( GROWLING )
- ( THUD ) - ( WHIMPERING GROAN )
( ECHOING GROWL )
Did you take him down from the tree ?
We don 't move the bodies .
What is it ?
A god .
Ancient .
One of the Jotunn .
( WHISPERS ) A bastard offspring of Loki .
We do not say its name .
Because you 're afraid of it ?
We worship it .
It keeps us here .
Let us live beyond natural life .
No more pain . No more death .
Your ritual begins tonight .
It is a privilege to worship .
You will kneel before the god .
If not , it will hang you from the trees .
Why me ?
Your pain is great .
Yeah , I 'm not like you , and I will not live like this .
You will kneel before it ,
like the rest of us .
( DOOR SHUTS )
( MUFFLED CHATTER )
( UNNATURAL WHISPERING )
( GASPS )
( MUFFLED CHATTER )
( UNNATURAL WHISPERING )
( CHATTER FADES )
( SHRIEKS )
( SCREAMS )
( MUTTERS )
( DISTANT SHOUTING )
( THUD )
( SHRIEKING )
( THUDDING FOOTFALLS )
( GROWLING )
( MAN YELLING IN THE DISTANCE )
Yes .
( UNNATURAL WHISPERING )
- ( WOMAN RESPONDS ) - ( GROWLS )
( WOMAN SCREAMS )
( GROWLING )
( GASPS )
( CREAKING )
( PANTING )
( SPEAKS SWEDISH )
Fuck off . Fuck off .
( GUN CLICKS )
Shit . ( GUN COCKS )
- ( SPEAKS SWEDISH ) - Fuck .
( GUNSHOT )
Drop the axe .
Stay there .
Stay there . Stay there . Stay there .
( CRACKING AND CREAKING )
( LOW GROWLING )
( CLATTERING AND THUDDING )
( GROANING AND PANTING )
( ECHOING CRY )
( GROWLS )
( PANTING )
( GUNSHOT )
( ROARS )
( PANTING )
( HOWLING )
( LUKE SCREAMS )
( GROWLING )
( GROANS )
( ROARS )
( HOWLING )
( STRANGE WHISPERING )
No . No .
( GROWLING )
( GROWLS )
( GRUNTS )
( GROWLING )
( STAMPING )
( LIGHT GROWL AND HEAVY BREATHING )
( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING )
( GROWLING )
( ROARS )
( YELLS )
( PAINED GROWLS )
( ECHOING ROAR )
( GROWLING )
( ROARING )
( LOW GROWLING )
( PANTING )
( FIERCE ROAR )
( YELLS )
( LOW GROWLING )
( HOWLING )
( YELLS )
Subtitles by explosiveskull